Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1815; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Congress has accepted his offer of his library; plans for restocking his personal library. Bur. of rolls, v.6,472 - Ser. 2,v.83,125. FILM 199 FRAME 259 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 22, 1815; 8" x 10 1/8"; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    Boston, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests letters of introduction, preparatory to voyage to Europe. Refers to Everett, Jefferson, Say, Seybert. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, March 24, 1815; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Leigh, Egerton, 1762-1818
    Washington hall, A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and end. Business. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Le Roy,Bayard & McEvers, New York, March 27, 1815; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add. (from original in Diederich Collection, 139 Cu 1, University of Amsterdam Library.) Concerning a claim made through Robert Walsh, and he might be able to help. MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 24, 1815; 8" x 12 5/8"; Freeman, James, 1759-1835
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Hancock. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 11, 1815; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. His catalogue of wants from France; remits sum to be placed in the hands of [Stephen] Girard for credit at Paris. Bur. of rolls, v.6,472 - Ser. 2,v.83,126. Contains also: Th. Jefferson to [J. Vaughan]; Monticello, July 15, 1815. S. Girard to Messrs. Perregaux Laffitte & co.; Phila., July 30, 1815. Stephen Girard to Messrs. Perregaux Laffitte & co.; Phila., July 30, 1815. FILM 199 FRAME 260 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], July 15, 1815; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. On same sheet with letter from Jefferson to Vaughan, July 11,1815. Business; follow up letter of July 11, 1815. FILM 199 FRAME 260 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 21, 1815; 8 1/4" x 9 3/8"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, 3 pp., address and endorsement. L. Unsigned. Regarding volcanic eruption on the moon. Refers to Professor Cleaveland. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 27, 1815; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquiries respecting the laws and finances of Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Messrs. Perregaux Laffitte & co., July 30, 1815; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. On same sheet with letter from T. Jefferson to John Vaughan, Financial transaction of Thomas Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 260 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Messrs. Perregaux Laffitte & co., July 30, 1815; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. On same sheet with letter from T. Jefferson to John Vaughan, July 11,1815. Financial transaction of Thomas Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 260 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 17, 1815; 8" x 9 3/4"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Göttingen, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.I. The University of Göttingen. Conditions in Europe. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1815; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Adams, John, 1735-1826
    Quincy, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Samuel Gilman. Regarding hurricane of 23d. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 29, 1815; 7 1/2" x 9 7/8"; Short, C. W.
    Cincinnati, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Drake of Cincinnati. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 8, 1815; 8 1/16" x 9 15/16"; Peck, William D.
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 3 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Concerning mistake made in distributing the plates for the third volume of Michaux's work. Suggests means of correction. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to (John) Vaughan, November 14, 1815; 7 1/4" x 9"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Recommendation of Mr. John Taylor. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 17, 1815; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Winchester, Va., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Will be in Philadelphia about January 3d. Account of visits in South Carolina. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans.n.s., V.45, part 2, p.138. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 3, 1816; McLane, Allan, 1746-1829
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Extract from biographical note of Geo. Logan, Feb., 1816; 7 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Logan, Deborah Norris, 1761-1839
    D. 1p. and end. Contains also a clipping from the American daily advertiser, July 12, 1837, about Dr. George Logan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Le Roy, Bayard & McEvers, New York, March 16, 1816; 10-1/2x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (from original in Diederich Collection, 139 Cu 2, University of Amsterdam Library.) Business of shipment from France. Refers to F.A.Michaux. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Certificate of membership issued to John Vaughan, May 23, 1816; 19" x 14"; Philadelphia Linnean Society
    Philadelphia, Printed D.S: Gulielmus P.C. Barton, praeses. In Latin. Oversize. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 10, 1816; Bollmann, Erick, 1769-1821
    London, Photostat of A.L.S. 3p. from Emmanul Collections new york public libirary MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 14, 1816; 7 7/8" x 10"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    Boston, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. "As yet unable to recommend to you a candidate for your church." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Joseph Priestley, September 17, 1816; 7 3/8" x 9"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    MSL-3 Philadelphia, 1 p. Letter-press copy. Concerning Priestley's son. Much of the letter is undecipherable. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 12, 1816; 8 1/8" x 10"; Freeman, James, 1759-1835
    Baltimore, 2pp., A.L.S. Will assist in founding Unitarian Church in Baltimore. Wishes to see Vaughan in Philadelphia, while on his way to Boston. Concerning the Unitarian Church. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Oct. 16, [1816]; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    (?) Photostat of A.L.S. On sheet with letter from F. Kinloch to Hassler. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 21, 1816; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Sullivan, John L. (John Langdon), 1777-1865
    Boston, 3pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the use of steam tow boats. Dispute with [Robert] Fulton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to (John) Vaughan, 1816; 7 1/2" x 12"; Framery
    ----, 2 pp. and endorsement. L. Unsigned. (In French.) Questions of the French consul relative to the United States. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1817; 8 1/4" x 10"; Brackenridge, H. M. (Henry Marie), 1786-1871
    Baltimore, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introduces Mr. Gilleland. Has published new edition of his Views of Louisiana. FILM 403 FRAME 5-3. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 6, 1817; 7 7/8" x 10"; Ferguson, James
    Charleston, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Relative to the health of Charleston. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 2, 1817; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Gilmer, Francis Walker, 1790-1826
    Winchester, Va., A.L.S. 2p.and add. Regarding Ticknor's description of "the mode of life among the German literati." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 11, 1817; 7 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Gottingen, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Acknowledges letters of recommendation fo himself and Mr. Ticknor. Mentions Michaux, Blumenbach, Correa, etc. ---- Copy typed (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 18, 1817; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Ramirez, Alexander
    Havana, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges letters of April 3 and 18; together with Talleyrand's pamphlets. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, June 7, 1817; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. Importation of books and wine from France; Mr. Vaughan, agent. FILM 199 FRAME 261 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 1, 1817; 7 3/4" x 10"; Sullivan, John L. (John Langdon), 1777-1865
    Boston, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Desires the influence of Mr. Vaughan's name in advocating the use of steam tow boats on the Delaware river. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 15, 1817; 8" x 9"; Freeman, James, 1759-1835
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing his niece Julia Davis. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 29, 1817; 7 3/4" x 9"; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Allan Pollock. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Oct. 4, 1817; Adams, Louisa Catherine, 1775-1852
    Washington, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Contains note by Jn. Vaughan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 30, 1817; 8" x 10"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Sends draft in payment for work relatives to indentures of Christina Neufer (?) and Philip Schaihing (?). MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 15, 1817; 8" x 9 3/4"; Adams, Louisa Catherine, 1775-1852
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Franked: Free J. Q. Adams. The German woman and boy arrived safe. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to J(oh)n Vaughan, December 1, 1817; 8 1/8" x 10"; Van der Kemp, Francis Adrian, 1752-1829
    Oldenbarneveld, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding his projected works on religion. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, December 10, 1817; 8" X 10"; Francis, John W.
    L-2 New York, With regard to appropriations made for educational purposes by the legislature of New York state. Mentions stories of sea monster. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 15, 1817; 8" x 9 3/4"; Bogert, G. G.
    New York, 1p. A.L.S. Introducing John Bradbury, who "has lately published in England his Journal in Louisiana and is solicitous to republish it in Philadelphia." FILM 403 FRAME 5-4. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan.2, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Trumbull, John, 1756-1843
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Introduces Dr. Brown of Kentucky. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has received request to become a candidate for professorship of anatomy at University (of Pennsylvania?). Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 20, 1818; 8" x 12 3/4"; Deas, William Allen
    ----, 5 pp., illustration, address and endorsement. A.Com.S. Method of boring for salt. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 27, 1818; 8" x 9 3/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Norfolk, (Va.), 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Personal letter. Will be detained at Norfolk by illness. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans. n.s., v.45, part 2, p.161. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, April 8, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Order for books and wines from France. FILM 199 FRAME 262 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839
    L-2 Hallowell, 3 pp., illustration, address and endorsement. A.Com.S. Description of newly constructed pump. Illustration of the same. Family news. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 3, 1818; 8" x 10"; Baldwin, Loammi, 1780-1838
    Cambridge, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Rufus Wyman and Cyrus Baldwin. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Messrs. Warcler and Brothers, May 19, 1818; 8 1/4" x 13", 7 3/4" x 13"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S.; 3 pp. D. Accounts concerned with sale of five bales woolens for Mr. Robert Oastler. Includes account of sales by Sam. Merrick, c. 1807-09. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 28, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L. in 3d. P. 1p. and add. and end. Thanks him for information respecting the competitions for the professorships; mentions Mr. Cooper. FILM 199 FRAME 263 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Messrs. LeRoy, Bayard & Co., New York, Aug. 1, 1818; 9 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Introduces his nephew, Petty Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 15, 1818; 7 1/2" x 9"; Bollmann, Erick, 1769-1821
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Purchase of platina (?). MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 3, 1818; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hopkinson, Joseph, 1770-1842
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Relative to the bankrupt law. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 20, 1819; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Samuel Eliot. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 24, 1819; 7 3/8" x 9 1/2"; Perkins, Samuel G.
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. Mr. Greenwood. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 22, 1819; 7 1/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Poplar Forest near Lynchburg, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Suffering from rheumatism. Financial transactions. Hopes to see Mr. Correa at Monticello some time within the month. FILM 199 FRAME 264 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Rules for a new settlement in Cuba, Oct., 1819; 13x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 5p.and end. From the Memorias of the Sociedad Royale de la Havanna. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 7, 1819; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Short, C. W.
    Hopkinsville, Ky., 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Has received religious tracts. Views on Unitarianism. Friendship with Dr. Barton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 6, 1819; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; De Saussure, Henry William, 1763-1839
    Columbia, S.C., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Mr. Cooper elected to professorship of chemistry at South Carolina College. See, Correa de Serra to J. R. Poinsett, October 20, 1819. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 20, 1819; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Professor Norton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 5, 1820; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Baltimore, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that he has been unable to obtain a review of Mr. Walsh's book for The North American Review. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, February 8, 1820; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 14, 1820; 8" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. $400 to be sent to Thomas Appleton of Leghorn. Refers to the university. FILM 199 FRAME 265 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 8, 1820; 8" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Progress of house for Dr. Cooper at University. Believes University will not open until February 1722 [i.e. 1822]. FILM 199 FRAME 266 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to ----, March 15, 1820; 8" x 10"; Taney, Roger Brooke, 1777-1864
    Frederick, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Regarding a court case. Refers to Mr. Routzon. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 9, 1820; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Seal of the University of Virginia; Dr. Cooper. FILM 199 FRAME 267 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 24, 1820; 8" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Seal of the University of Virginia. Dr. Cooper; Mr. Correa. Finances. FILM 199 FRAME 268 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 13, 1820; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. and add. and end. Financial transactions. FILM 199 FRAME 269 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 8, 1820; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844
    Washington, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Unitarians in Washington need an organ. New England Unitarians want to found church; need money. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 9, 1820; 8 1/8" x 10"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding subscriptions to newspapers and magazines. Printed: Davis, Abbé Correa, APS trans.n.s.45, pt.2, 1955, 183. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 29, 1820; 7 5/8" x 12 1/8"; Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839
    L-2 Hallowell, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires about the probable success of the sale of a patent for a new beehive. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 30, 1821; 7 1/4" x 9 1/2"; Jones, C.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses remarks and estimate of cost of steam boat, as required by Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 30, 1821; 7 1/4" x 9 1/2"; Jones, C.
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. Com. Description and estimate of cost of a steam boat to answer the purposes required by Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to (John) Vaughan, March 9, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Patterson, James, 1779-1837
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Submits estimate of prices of steam engines and boilers. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 10, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Queen, Robert M.
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Estimates cost of constructing steam engine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 8, 1821; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Too soon to consier Mr. Vanuxem in connection with staff of University. FILM 199 FRAME 27 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to (John Vaughan), April 23, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, 2 pp. A.L.S. Activity in England and France. Wishes to be remembered to his friends in Philadelphia. Election of William Vaughan to the Royal Linnean Society. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans.,n.s., v.45, part 2, p.184. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 7, 1821; 7 1/4" x 9"; Cheverus, Jean-Louis-Anne-Madeleine Lefebvre de, 1768-1836
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introduces Mr. Haddock. Wishes to be remembered to Dr. Edward Barton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 10, 1821; 7 7/8" x 10"; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    London, 3pp. and address. A.L.S. Had pleasure of meeting Dr. Seybert in London. Work upon natural history for Museum of East India Company. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J.H. Jackson, May 27, 1821; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Belmont, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Flax machines. The depression. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Jo(hn) Vaughan, June 26, 1821; 7 3/16" x 8 7/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Personal letter. Conditions in England. Printed: Davis, Abbé Correa, APS Trans. n.s.45, pt.2, 1955, 185. Formerly MISC. MS. COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J(ohn) Vaughan, June 28, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S. C., 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Duties connected with his work at South Carolina College. Personal affairs. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 1, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S. C., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. McCord. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 27, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S. C., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Illness of Mrs. DeSaussure. Wishes correct copy of plate showing Capt. Kater's improved pendulum. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 24, 1821; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Turner, William
    Newcastle, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to the progress of Warrington Academy. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 27, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Francis, John W. (John Wakefield), 1789-1861
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Thomas Agg. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 7, 1821; 8" x 10"; Barton, Edward, d. 1821
    Genoa, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Discomforts of sea travel. Ill health. Has not heard from friends in Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, December 27, 1821; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Polanen, R. G. van
    New York, 2 pp. A.L.S. Regarding the bankruptcy law in Holland. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], January 13, 1822; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    3 pp. A.L.S. Personal letter. Ill health of Edward Barton. Wishes to be remembered to his friends in Philadelphia. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans., n.s., v.45, part 2 p.186. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J(ohn) Vaughan, January 19, 1822; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Lisbon, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Unfavorable impression of Lisbon. Wishes to be remembered to his friends in Philadelphia. Printed: Davis, Abbé Correa, APS, Trans. n.s.45, pt. 2, 1955, 187. Formerly MISC. MS. COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 1, 1822; 5" x 7 3/4"; Miller, William
    ----, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding payment of insurance, in 1805, on goods condemned as prize in the Marine Tribunal of St. Leon. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 28, 1822; 8 1/8" x 9 5/8"; Tudor, W.
    Boston, A.L.S. Forwards "a copy of proposals for a book he hopes to publish this summer. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 13, 1822; 8" x 9 7/8"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introduces the Rev. Dr. Tuckerman. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 13, 1822; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Toulmin, Harry, 1766-1823
    Washington, C. H., Alabama, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Personal letter. Description of the country and its condition in his vicinity. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 25, 1822; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Thacher, Peter Oxenbridge, 1776-1843
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introduces Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Longfellow, Jr., of Portland, Maine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan ?], June 20, 1822; 8" x 10"; Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de, 1766-1847
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. Business. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 10, 1822; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Placement of member of Dr. Wistar's family in U.S. Navy. Bur. of rolls, v.10,20 - Ser. 6,v.15,76. FILM 199 FRAME 271 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 14, 1822; 8" x 9"; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introduces David A. Hall, his son in law. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.